Fund for Adult Education (FAE) Records
Fund for Adult Education (FAE) Records
- Experimental discussion Project
  - EDP
    - Life Under Communism
      - Fort Atkinson, Wisc., 1953 (Box 60)
      - Garden City, N.Y., 1953 (Box 61)
      - Lima, Ohio, 1953 (Box 61)
      - Lincoln, Neb., 1953 (Box 61)
      - Memphis, Tenn., 1953 (Box 61)
      - New York City, 1953 (Box 61)
      - Niagara Falls, N.Y., 1953 (Box 61)
      - Palo Alto, Cal., 1953 (Box 61)
      - Pasadena, Cal., 1953; 2 folders (Box 61)
      - Rochester, N.Y., 1953 (Box 61)
      - Rockford, Ill., 1953 (Box 61)
      - All Cities Analysis, 1953 (Box 62)
      - Evaluations, 1953 (Box 62)
      - Evaluation tabulations, 1953 (Box 62)
      - Summary questionnaire, 1953 (Box 62)
    - Looking at Modern Painting
      - Test Group reports, 1957 (Box 62)
      - Evaluations, 1959 (Box 62)
    - Economic Reasoning, 1955; evaluation and problem analysis reports (Box 62)
    - An Introduction to the Humanities, 1959; group leaders evaluation (Box 63)
    - "Let's Talk About...", 1953-1954; end of meeting evaluation form (Box 63)
    - Leading Croup discussion, 1954-1958; evaluation (Box 63)
    - Evaluation procedures and related matters, 1952-1959 (Box 63)
    - Summary analysis sheet, circa 1955 (Box 63)
    - Wyoming film discussion project, 1953; final report (Box 63)
  - EFDP
    - Baltimore, Md., Eastern Community Council, 1952 (Box 64)
    - Birmingham, Ala., Citizens Group, 1952; 2 folders (Box 64)
    - Boston, Mass., Public Library, 60 plus group, 1952; 2 folders (Box 64)
    - Bountiful, Utah, Special Interest, M.I.A., 1952 (Box 64)
    - Brooklyn, N.Y., Brooklyn Public Library, 1952 (Box 64)
    - Brooklyn, N.Y., U.S. Maritime Service Officers' Club, 1952 (Box 65)
    - Buffalo, N.Y., Buffalo Public Library, 1952; 2 folders (Box 65)
    - Chapel Hill, N.C., Civic Club Representatives, 1952 (Box 65)
    - Chattanooga, Tenn., Public Library, 1952; 2 folders (Box 65)
    - Chicago, Ill., Lawson, YMCA, 1952 (Box 65)
    - Chicago, Ill., Roosevelt College, 1952 (Box 66)
    - Coachella, Cal., Public School (Adult), 1952 (Box 66)
    - Columbia, Mo., Stephens College, 1952 (Box 66)
    - Dallas, Tex., Church Group, 1952; 2 folders (Box 66)
    - Dayton, Ohio, YMCA, 1952 (Box 66)
    - Dayton, Ohio, Council On World Affairs, 1952 (Box 67)
    - Des Moines, Iowa, Adult Education Executive Committee, 1952 (Box 67)
    - Detroit, Mich., Public Library, 1952 (Box 67)
    - Flint, Mich., Mott Foundation, Adult Education, 1952 (Box 67)
    - Fort Atkinson, Wisc., Dwight Foster Public Library, 1952 (Box 67)
    - Great Falls, Mont., Farmer-Labor Institute, 1952; 2 folders (Box 67, 68)
    - Lions Club, 1952 (Box 68)
    - Griffin, Ga., Business and Professional Women, 1952 (Box 68)
    - Kennett, Mo., County Library, 1952 (Box 68)
    - La Crosse, Wisc., Public Library, 1952; 2 folders (Box 68)
    - Laramie, Wyo., University, 1952 (Box 68)
    - Lincoln, Neb., Public School, 1952; 2 folders (Box 69)
    - Manhattan, Kansas, Library, 1952 (Box 69)
    - Memphis, Tenn., Southwestern University, 1952; 2 folders (Box 69)
    - Minneapolis, Minn., Public Library, 1952 (Box 69)
    - New Philadelphia, Ohio, Library, 1952 (Box 70)
    - New York Junior League, 1952 (Box 70)
    - Pasadena, Cal.
      - Married Couples Monday Evening, 1952; 2 folders (Box 70)
      - Rotary Club, 1952; 2 folders (Box 70)
      - Senior Citizen Club, 1952; 2 folders (Box 71)
      - Young Adults, 1952 (Box 71)
    - Petersburg, Va., Virginia State College, 1952; 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Portland, Ore., Public Library, 1952 (Box 71)
    - Price, Utah, Carbon College, 1952 (Box 71)
    - Reading, Pa., T.E.A. discussion Group, 1952 (Box 71)
    - Rhinelander, Wisc., Public Library, 1952; 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Rochester, N.Y., R.A.U.N., 1952 (Box 72)
    - St. Louis, Mo., Council on World Affairs, 1952; 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Salina, Kansas, Library, 1952; 2 folders (Box 72)
    - San Francisco, Cal., World Affairs Council, 1952 (Box 73)
    - San Bernardino, Cal., Valley College, 1952; 2 folders (Box 73)
    - San Jose, Cal., Adult Center, 1952 (Box 73)
    - Santa Monica, Cal., S.M. Bay Women's Club, 1952 (Box 73)
    - Sioux City, Iowa, Adult Education, Schools, 1952 (Box 73)
    - Shorewood, Wisc., Women's Club, 1952; 2 folders (Box 73, 74)
    - Snyder, N.Y., Public School Adult Education, 1952 (Box 74)
    - Stamford, Conn., Ferguson Library, 1952 (Box 74)
    - Worthington, Minn., Library, 1952 (Box 74)
    - Attendance Records, 1952 (Box 74)
    - End-of-meeting evaluation forms, 1952 (Box 74)
    - Group member report, 1952 (Box 74)
    - International Understanding Series
      - Group member reports, 1952; 4 folders (Box 75)
    - Group summary questionnaires,by state, 1952; 5 folders (Box 76)
- Personal information
  - Discussion groups, 1957; 164 folders (Box 77-86)
  - Discussion groups, 1958; 40 folders (Box 86-88)
- Group information
  - Akron, University of, Institute for Civic Education, 1957 (Box 88)
  - Arkansas, University of, 1957 (Box 88)
  - British Columbia, University of, 1958 (Box 88)
  - California, University of, Los Angeles, 1957-1958; 4 folders (Box 88)
  - Kansas City, University of, 1958 (Box 88)
  - Louisville, University of, 1957-1958 (Box 88)
  - Pasadena Liberal Arts Center, 1957-1958; 2 folders (Box 88)
  - Whittier Liberal Arts Center, 1957-1958; 2 folders (Box 88)
  - Analysis of Test Center Data, 1958-1959 (Box 88)
- Group leader's reactions
  - Twin Cities Liberal Arts Center, 1957-1958 (Box 89)
  - Utah, University of, Salt Lake City, 1957 (Box 89)
  - Virginia, University of, Richmond Center, 1957-1958 (Box 89)
  - British Columbia, University of, 1958; 4 folders (Box 89)
  - California, University of, Los Angeles, 1958; 4 folders (Box 89)
  - Charlottesville, Va., 1958 (Box 89)
  - Kansas City, University of, 1958 (Box 89)
  - Louisville, University of, 1958 (Box 89)
  - Pasadena Liberal Arts Center, 1958 (Box 89)
  - St. Paul, 1958 (Box 89)
  - Twin Cities Liberal Arts Center, 1958 (Box 89)
  - Utah, University of, Salt Lake City, 1958 (Box 89)
  - Virginia, University of, Richmond Center, 1958 (Box 89)
  - Whittier Liberal Arts Center, 1958; 2 folders (Box 89)
- Newspaper clippings and photostats
  - Akron Beacon Journal, 1952-1964; 5 folders (Box 90)
  - Educational Television Factsheet, Box Score, Nov 1954 - May 1960 (Box 90)
  - Various, 1951-1960; 4 folders (Box 91)
  - Test Cities editorials, 1953-1958 (Box 91)
  - News releases and press clippings, 1959-1960; 2 folders (Box 92)
  - Foundations, 1951-1958 (Box 92)
  - Memphis newspaper clippings, 1957-1964; 2 folders (Box 92)
  - Magazine summaries, 1958-1959 (Box 92)
  - Various, 1954-1959 (Box 93)
  - Magazine summaries, 1950-1959 (Box 93)
  - Educational Television, 1952-1958 (Box 93)
  - Newsletters, 1953-1960 (Box 93)
  - Public Responsibility; Leadership; Liberal Education, 1959-1960 (Box 93)
  - Educational Television, 1959-1960 (Box 93)
  - Foundations and Funds, 1959 (Box 94)
  - News releases and press clippings, editorial comments, 1959 (Box 94)
  - George E. Sokolsky column, 1959 (Box 94)
  - Memphis newspaper clippings, 1952-1961; 3 folders (Box 94)
  - Various, 1960 (Box 95)
  - Magazine summaries, 1956-1960 (Box 95)
  - News releases and press clippings, 1959 (Box 95)
  - Various, 1961 (Box 96)
  - Inside Channels (Newsletter), 1956-1960 (Box 96)
  - News Digest, 1959-1960 (Box 96)
- The Study Of Sioux City
  - Miscellaneous, 1955-1956 (Box 95)
- Publications
  - Printed publications
    - America Armed: Essays on United States Military Policy, ed. R.A. Goldwin; Rand McNally & Company, Chicago, [third printing, 1969]. (Box 97)
    - Beyond the Cold War: Essays on American Foreign Policy in a Changing World Environment, ed. R.A. Goldwin; Rand McNally & Company, Chicago, [1965]. (Box 97)
    - Higher Education and Modern Democracy, ed. R.A. Goldwin; Rand McNally & Company, Chicago, [1965]. (Box 97)
    - Left, Right, and Center: Essays on Liberalism and Conservatism in the United States, ed. R.A. Goldwin; Rand McNally & Company, Chicago [1965]. (Box 97)
    - A Nation of Cities: Lssays on America's Urban Problems, ed. R.A. Goldwin; Rand McNally & Company, Chicago, [1967]. (Box 97)
    - A Nation of States: Essays on the American Federal System, ed. R.A. Goldwin; Rand McNally & Company, Chicago, [sixth printing, 1969]. (Box 97)
    - Political Parties, U.S.A., ed. R,A. Goldwin; Rand. McNally & Company, Chicago, [third printing, 1968]. (Box 97)
    - Representation and Misrepresentation, ed. R.A. Goldwin; Rand McNally & Ccmpany, Chicago,[1967]. (Box 97)
    - Studies in Adult Group Learning in the Liberal Arts, 4 vols., by John Walker Powell; The Fund for Adult Education, 1960. (Box 97)
    - Why Foreign Aid?: Two Messages by President Kennedy and Essays, ed. R.A. Goldwin; Rand McNally & Company, Chicago, [1963]. (Box 97)
    - Civic Education in the United States: A Directory of Organizations, comps. Robert Horowitz and Carl Tjerandsen; The University of Chicago, 1954; with 1958-59 Supplement. (Box 97)
  - Miscellaneous publications
    - The Challenge of Lifetime Learning, ContinuingLiberal Education, report, 1955-1957 (Box 97)
    - Solution of the Functionally Illiterate Problem, 1968 (Box 97)
    - The 10th Annual Seminar on Leadership in University Adult Education, 1967 (Box 97)
    - Liberal Education: summary of a discussion by the Trustees of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1956 (Box 97)
    - Opinions of School Superintendents on Adult Education, 1964 (Box 97)
    - Statistics of Public School Adult Education, 1958-1959 (Box 97)
    - Survey of University Adult Education in the Metropolitan Area of New York, 1966-1967 (Box 97)
- FAE Part 2: 1991 additions
  This addition consists of correspondence, memoranda, reports, essays, news releases and seminar summaries. Most of the files supplement the material in part one on Experimental discussion groups (EDP). There are also three folders related to the Cooperative Extension Services Project in Public Affairs and for Public Responsibilities. General files precede those of the Cooperative Extension project. These are followed by the EDP files. Within these groupings, material is arranged alphabetically.
  - News releases, 1960-1961 (Box 98)
  - Problems and solutions, 1957
    - Developing discussion materials (Box 98)
    - Developing course and Program materials (Box 98)
    - Self-Supporting Centers of Liberal Education (Box 98)
    - Coordinating Education and Television (Box 98)
    - Leadership Training Awards (Box 98)
  - Proposals, University College, Syracuse University, 1960 (Box 98)
  - Recommendations, Development Committee on Internships, Scholarships and Fellowships, 1953 (Box 98)
  - Cooperative Extension Services Project
    - Memoranda, 1959-1960 (Box 98)
    - Seminar summaries, 1959 (Box 98)
    - Seminar tour, Program consultants, misc., 1959 (Box 98)
  - Experimental discussion groups
    - Article, "Discussion groups - A Leftist Trap", 1957 (Box 98)
    - Correspondence, responses to Mr. Fletcher's letter, 1954 (Box 98)
    - Life Under Communism
      - Essays, 1953 (Box 98)
      - Memoranda, Reading lists, Progress report, misc., 1953 (Box 98)
    - Reports
      - Preliminary report, Liberal Arts discussion groups, 1956 (Box 98)
      - Report, "A Preliminary Exploration of U.S. Communities Using Study-Discussion Program materials, 1956-1958 (Box 98)
      - Progress report, 1957 (Box 98)
  - Experimental film discussion project, progress report, 1952 (Box 98)
- Audiorecordings
  - "All the World's a Stage" (A Study in Status and Role), 01/25/1955; fae_073; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 6 - "Who Do You Think You Are"; running time 28:30; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 8)
  - "All the World's a Stage" (A Study in Status and Role), 01/25/1955; fae_074; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 6 - "Who Do You Think You Are"; running time 28:30; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 8)
  - "Bigwin Inn", 09/07/1953; fae_005; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - "But I Know What I Like" (A Study in the Arts), 02/01/1953; fae_079; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 12; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 8)
  - "The Case of the Bamboo Sized Pigs", 06/19/1953; fae_085; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 2; running time 27:02; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 9)
  - "The Case of the Bamboo Sized Pigs", 06/19/1953; fae_086; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 2; running time 27:02; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 9)
  - "The Case of the Borrowed Wife", 06/29/1953; fae_083; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 1; running time 28:46; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 8)
  - "The Case of the Borrowed Wife", 06/29/1953; fae_084; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 1; running time 28:46; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 8)
  - "The Case of the Sea-Lion Flippers" (A Study in Ethics), fae_065; Ways of Mankind Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 7)
  - "The Case of the Sea-Lion Flippers" (A Study in Ethics), 01/25/1955; fae_067; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 8 - "The Right Thing"; running time 29:43; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 7)
  - "The Danger of Freedom", fae_015; From Program 6 "Freedom of Opinion"; Part of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - "The Danger of Freedom", fae_023; Part of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - "The Democrat and the Commissar" and "Light and Liberty", fae_021; Program #2 and #4 of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - "The Democrat and the Commissar", fae_016; From Program 7 "The Nature of the Revolution"; Part of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - "Desert Soliloquy": A Study in Education, fae_061; Ways of Mankind Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 7)
  - "Desert Soliloquy": A Study in Education, fae_062; Ways of Mankind Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 7)
  - "Desert Soliloquy": A Study in Education, fae_063; Ways of Mankind Series; running time 30:02; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 7)
  - "Divided We Stand", fae_011; From Program 2 "Freedom of Religion"; Part of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - "Divided We Stand", fae_022; Part of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - Dm Carlo, 04/04/1959; fae_097; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 10)
  - End of an Era, fae_001; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - "The Everlasting Struggle for Freedom", fae_010; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - "The Experience of a Free Press", fae_014; From Program 5 "Freedom of the Press"; Part of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - "The Forbidden Name of Wednesday", fae_091; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 4: "The Quality of Justice"; running time 28:22; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 9)
  - "The Forbidden Name of Wednesday", fae_092; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 4: "The Quality of Justice"; running time 28:22; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 9)
  - "Freedom of the Press" and "The University of the United States", fae_025; Part of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - "Freeing the Land", fae_013; From Program 4 "Economic Freedom"; Part of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - "The Ground of Justice", fae_017; From Program 8 "Ground of Justice"; Part of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - "The Grounds of Justice", fae_024; Part of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - "Home Sweet Home" (A Study in Family), 01/25/1955; fae_075; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 10; running time 27:22; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 8)
  - "Home Sweet Home" (A Study in Family), 01/25/1955; fae_076; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 10; running time 27:22; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 8)
  - Interviews by George Martin with Paul G. Hoffman, fae_054; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 6)
  - Jeff and Our Times, fae_008; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Jeff and Our Times, fae_009; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - "Laying Down the Law", fae_093; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 6; running time 28:36; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 9)
  - "Laying Down the Law", fae_094; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 6; running time 28:36; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 9)
  - "Legend of the Long House" (A Study in Authority), 07/03/1952; fae_069; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 9 - "The Constituted Power"; running time 27:08; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 7)
  - "Legend of the Long House" (A Study in Authority), 07/03/1952; fae_070; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 9 - "The Constituted Power"; running time 27:08; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 7)
  - The Liberal Arts and the Government of Men by President Arthur Flemming, 02/25/1958; fae_034; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - The Liberal Arts and the Government of Men by President Arthur Flemming, 02/26/1958; fae_035; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - The Liberal Arts and the Government of Men by President Arthur Flemming, 02/27/1958; fae_036; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - "Light and Liberty", fae_012; From Program 3 "Scientific Freedom"; Part of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - "Lion Bites Man", fae_089; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 4: "The Quality of Justice"; running time 29:22; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 9)
  - "Lion Bites Man", fae_090; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 4: "The Quality of Justice"; running time 29:22; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 9)
  - "The Living Declaration", 04/04/1952; fae_020; Part of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - Lowell Institute Cooperative Broadcasting Council: American Literature, 07/04/1952; fae_037; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 5)
  - Lowell Institute Cooperative Broadcasting Council: Anthology (1 of 2), 07/11/1952; fae_038; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 5)
  - Milton Katz, 05/22/1953; fae_053; running time 28:20; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 6)
  - "Museum of Man" (A Study in Society), 07/11/1952; fae_080; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 13; running time 26:22; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 8)
  - "Museum of Man" (A Study in Society), 07/11/1952; fae_081; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 13; running time 26:22; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 8)
  - "Museum of Man" (A Study in Society), 07/11/1952; fae_082; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 13; running time 26:22; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 8)
  - Music for "Humanities" Groupe, 06/05/1962; fae_006; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Music for Humanities Unit VI and VII, 06/05/1962; fae_007; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Musical Selections No. 1, fae_004; running time 10:59; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Musical Selections Record No. 2, 09/06/1955; fae_002; Crucifixus; 2nd Fuge; Mozart Aonata; Chopin Prelude #6; Chopin Prelude #13; running time 14:16; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Musical Terms Record, 08/27/1955; fae_003; running time 10:59; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - "Nature's Most Precious Gifts", fae_019; From Program 10 "Leadership in a Free Society"; Part of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - People Under Communism: "Drama to Order" (1 of 2), 06/05/1962; fae_045; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 5)
  - People Under Communism: "Drama to Order" (2 of 2), 06/05/1962; fae_046; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 5)
  - People Under Communism: "Literature to Order" (1 of 2), 06/05/1962; fae_047; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 5)
  - People Under Communism: "Literature to Order" (2 of 2), 06/05/1962; fae_048; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 5)
  - People Under Communism: "Music to Order" (1 of 2), 06/05/1962; fae_041; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 5)
  - People Under Communism: "Music to Order" (2 of 2), 06/05/1962; fae_042; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 5)
  - People Under Communism: "Pattern of World Conflict" (1 of 2), 06/05/1962; fae_049; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 6)
  - People Under Communism: "Pattern of World Conflict" (2 of 2), 06/05/1962; fae_050; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 6)
  - People Under Communism: "Terror as a System of Power" (1 of 2), 06/05/1962; fae_039; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 5)
  - People Under Communism: "Terror as a System of Power" (2 of 2), 06/05/1962; fae_040; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 5)
  - People Under Communism: "The Men Who Make the Migs" (1 of 2), 06/05/1962; fae_043; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 5)
  - People Under Communism: "The Men Who Make the Migs" (2 of 2), 06/05/1962; fae_044; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 5)
  - People Under Communism: "The Music and the Dream" (1 of 2), 06/05/1962; fae_051; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 6)
  - People Under Communism: "The Music and the Dream" (2 of 2), 06/05/1962; fae_052; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 6)
  - Randall Lectures: Lecture 1, fae_031; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - Randall Lectures: Lecture 2, fae_032; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - Randall Lectures: Lecture 3, fae_033; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - Reason and Discontent, fae_028; Part of the Bryson Lectureship; Dr. Lyman; Program 1; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - Reason and Discontent, fae_029; Part of the Bryson Lectureship; Dr. Lyman; Program 2; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - Reason and Discontent, fae_030; Part of the Bryson Lectureship; Dr. Lyman; Program 3; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - "The Repentant Horse Thief ", 06/30/1953; fae_087; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 3; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 9)
  - "The Repentant Horse Thief ", 06/30/1953; fae_088; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 3; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 9)
  - "Stand in for Murder" and "Design for Living", fae_060; running time 29:12; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 6)
  - "Stand in for Murder": A Study in Culture, fae_058; Ways of Mankind Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 6)
  - "Sticks and Stones" (A Study in Religion), 01/18/1953; fae_068; Ways of Mankind Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 7)
  - "Survival" (A Study in Technology), 01/02/1953; fae_077; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 11; running time 29:30; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 8)
  - "Survival" (A Study in Technology), 01/02/1953; fae_078; Ways of Mankind Series: Program 11; running time 29:30; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 8)
  - "To Secure These Rights" and "Nature's Most Precious Gifts", fae_026; Part of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; Programs 11-12; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - "University of the U.S.", fae_018; From Program 9 "Men's Right to Learn"; Part of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - "What the Jeffersonian Heritage Means Today", fae_027; Part of the "Jeffersonian Heritage" Series; Programs 13; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 4)
  - "Word in Your Ear" or "Watch Your Language", fae_059; Ways of Mankind Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 6)
  - "Word in Your Ear", fae_056; "Worth Your Language"; "Ways of Mankind"; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 6)
  - "Word in Your Ear", fae_057; "Watch Your Language"; running time 30:25; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 6)
  - "You Are Not Alone" (A Study in Groups), 01/04/1953; fae_071; Ways of Mankind Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 7)
  - "You Are Not Alone" (A Study in Groups), 01/04/1953; fae_072; Ways of Mankind Series; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 7)
  - The Years Between, fae_095; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 9)
  - What's With Music, fae_096; Krasner Sessions; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 9)
  - When Greek Meets Greek: Program 7 "What's Important to You?", 01/25/1955; fae_064; Ways of Mankind Series; running time 29:44; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 7)
  - When Greek Meets Greek: Program 7 "What's Important to You?", 01/25/1955; fae_066; Ways of Mankind Series; running time 29:44; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 7)